EUGENE KIM

Johns Creek, GA 30097 • ekim1707@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/eugene-kim-1707

JAVASCRIPT SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Expert, disciplined learner of new technologies and languages as pertaining to software development project goals; passionately curious of all disciplines relating to progress and general welfare of the community. Strong grasp of agile work environments and flexibility to adapt in order to optimize overall success. Strong understanding of position of physicians/medical providers in respect to clients; life-long student of the health sciences and medicine. Proven track record of stellar work ethic and devotion to team goals at every step along the journey.

Expertise

- Full-Stack Web Development
- SQL Queries & Data Modeling
- Strong Analytical/Critical Thinking Skills
- Ability to Learn New Technologies Quickly
- Application Development & Collaboration
- Debugging/Troubleshooting
- Understanding of Healthcare Industry
- Fluency in Medical Terminology

Professional Experience

React Intern, HEARBK, Atlanta, GA

Dec 2019 to Present

Collaborated remotely with lead developer on two-person development team to build mobile application for Atlanta-based startup intending to provide a platform for aspiring artists to be heard by uploading their music and gaining recognition from top music influencers and fans.

Project Highlights:

- Worked with MERN-stack to make responsive and interactive mobile application.
- Contributed bulk of React-Redux front-end components and facilitated back-end to front-end.
- Contributed significant debugging of both back-end and front-end, along with general troubleshooting of issues including but not limited to AWS deployment.
- Continuing assistance in any role, including maintenance and troubleshooting.

Partner and Manager, KIM FAMILY LLC, Ellicott City, MD

Jun 2008 to Present

Kim Family LLC is a family real-estate investment and management business.

Project Highlights:

 Aiding all efforts to manage assets effectively, including financial matters, research and decision-making, and daily maintenance.

Professional Experience (continued):

Assistant Manager, THE TUTORING CENTER, Johns Creek, GA

Nov 2018 to May 2019

Served as second-in-command for owner of local tutoring center franchise specializing in instruction of K-12/SAT/ACT students.

Project Highlights:

- Coordinated all tutors; managed all classroom procedures.
- Taught whenever necessary; served as PRN tutor for drop-in SAT/ACT students.
- Implemented use of Google/Amazon learning apps during all primary education classes.

Senior Analyst Advisor, IFPA INC., Teaneck, NJ

Jan 2017 to Nov 2017

Junior Analyst

Sep 2016 to Dec 2016

Served as manager of company's database and led inventory management efforts. IFPA is a large-scale, worldwide parts-manufacturer and distributer, and the main supplier for Herman Miller.

Project Highlights:

- Changed organizational scheme for storing inventory data; re-wrote master database.
- Aided in research efforts regarding product development and cost allocation.
- Attended executive meetings and gave presentations regarding ideas and research findings.

Healthcare Experience

PRN/Tech, CCDDC, Westminster, MD

Aug 2015 to Oct 2016

Spent start of second semester of RN program working with a 10+ member patient-care unit of Carroll County Digestive Disease Center to provide optimal care to all admitted endoscopy patients.

Project Highlights:

- Successfully prioritized and balanced all required duties throughout each shift.
- Received further training of and eventually mastered proper patient-care techniques.

Student, Registered Nursing Program, HCC, Columbia, MD

Jan 2015 to May 2016

Attended three semesters of the RN program at Howard Community College.

Project Highlights:

- Coordinated with nurses to provide full patient care throughout acute/long-term care facilities.
- Practiced proper documentation methods and adhered to specific healthcare provider protocol.

PT Shadow, CENTRAL MARYLAND REHABILITATION, Westminster, MD May 2011 to Jun 2013 Shadowed several physical therapists and physical therapist assistants and assisted when needed.

ekim1707@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/eugene-kim-1707

Education

Howard Community College, Columbia, MD UMBC, Baltimore, MD

Bachelor of Arts in Biology, GPA: 3.296, Aug 2012

Boston College, Chestnut Hill, MA

Software Development Portfolio

HearBK Mobile, website

Sep 2019

Music feedback app includes premium/basic users, payment methods, media uploads, more.

MERN-stack.

PeachtreeData.com, demo, website, github

Sep 2019

Wrote social-media/life-database site with connections, newsfeed, media-page, notepad, more.

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, React, and Redux.

Insta.id, demo, website, github

Aug 2019

Led 3-person development team in building an app to serve as an everyday ID-verification tool.

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, Express, and PostgreSQL.

OWRPG, demo, github

Jul 2019

Wrote large-scale, multi-layered RPG game incorporating the video game Overwatch.

Python.

Technology Summary

Applications: Adobe XD, Postico, Postman, Microsoft Office, Medical Mastermind, gGastro

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Sass, SQL, Python, C#
Frameworks: Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Redux.js, Bootstrap

Other: jQuery, RESTful API, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Trello,

Jenkins, AWS (EC2, Elastic Beanstalk, Amplify, more), Heroku, Netlify, NGINX,

Apache2, PM2

Leadership and Awards

Phi Theta Kappa Honors Society, Howard Community College, Mar 2015 Secretary of Student Government, Howard Community College, Aug 2013 to Dec 2013 Co-chair of Student Senate, Howard Community College, Aug 2013 to Dec 2013 Sigma Alpha Lambda National Leadership and Honors Organization, UMBC, Aug 2009 Golden Key International Honors Society, UMBC, Sep 2008